Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 45 in this exercise, we are asked to write a function
to delete a nod from blank bless since every note therefore linked list is dynamically allocated using
look in see we need to call free method for freeing memory allocated for that not to be deleted.
This has happened in C.
Now let's see how in Java this would be implemented.
We have created the non before and the aesthetic class not that contains the data and the next.
And we have created the methods like print last, push at, beginning, insert after and append not.
These are that insertion.
These are the insertion methods.
This is the print list.
And now let's see that deleting operations and link list.
OK.
Before we start, please go back and review their lecture about deleting their nodes and in order to
continue with us with this lecture and be familiar with everything, OK?
So for that, I will create public.
Void, delete, delete, not OK.
It took into the perimeter there, and so I need the key from the not given a key delete the first appearance
of the key and link it less.
So first of all, the first method store had not.
OK, so we start by not -- equal to hand and not.
Pretty equal to none.
OK.
This is how do we incent instantiate that them?
And they're a proof.
If the head itself holds the key to be deleted, then we check
if key or if and if had is the key is equal to the key, then delete their hand.
So if that does not equal to null, does not equal to null and then the data equal, equal to key.
This is happens so them or have had equal to hand equal to 10 dot next.
OK.
This will change their hand to return and break out from this if statement.
This is the case if habit is equal to the key so we can delete the head and move it to the next.
OK, now let's see that third case or the third step.
If.
The key is not the first, the first, not.
We need to search for that key.
So searching the third step is searching for that key to be deleted.
Keep the previous note.
I will put all this note in order to put it to write them down and not in New York.
Copy book into your notebook, please, guys.
These four are very important details, and you may ask it about them in the university or in there
at the interview.
OK, so why are they doing this if if it is the first not, we are deleting the head and move it to
the next of the head, and then we are going to search for the key to be deleted.
So keep their previous not as we need to change.
OK.
While them does not equal to none and then the data does not equal to key then.
Then.
Produce equal to 10 and stamp equal to attempt next.
OK, this is very important.
Now.
If key, if key was not present in the link at this.
As a programmer or a professional coder, you need to go and gather all that.
Possibilities lay the first one if the head is equal to the key that we are searching for.
To be deleted or if it is in any position, may be last, may be middle.
And here, if it is not the present itself, we are going to delete a key or ignored that it is not
the presented in the linked list.
So consider if we have 10 nods from one to 10 and have the data from one to 10, and we are searching
for a 12 key, a key equal to 12 for in this link list to be deleted.
It's very obvious that we will not delete anything because 12 is not presented inside this linked list,
so ask them equal if what to know if I'm sorry equally for two null, then return.
OK.
Now, after deleting this is a very important step, very important, very important.
After deleting after deletion.
Don't miss to unlink, then not only then not from the link, at least length and on
from the link list.
OK, how to do that by making brave dot lame or next equal to Camp Dot next.
OK, this is very important to break there.
And don't miss the link.
OK.
This is very important because we have deleted the note, but the reference and the the linking, the
then on inside the inside the link, at least to the next note, it would be not clear because we have
deleted not so we need to unlink, then nod from the link at least and move it to them the next.
So previous equals attempt.
OK, next.
This one will cover the problem and allow you to delete whatever you want from the list.
OK, so let's test this.
Method before we we call it, I would show you our current link list.
It's four, one, two, five, three and six.
I'm going to delete number two.
OK, so I will search inside the linked list.
Four g equals to do.
And then deleted, so the link and the new link at least, would be the same as this, but without too.
Let's see.
Let's go to the main and I will put here
exercise number 45
deleting and not linked list.
Don't delete.
No, and I passed the key.
It will search for two and will delete that sentence.
And here we go, guys.
Number two data or key does not exist, so the note that contains number two has been successfully deleted.
And this is what we need from you to understand that these things, these methods are being asked in
every interview, in every universe, the exams and data structures and algorithms subjects.
So pay attention for this and write them down because they are.